Neumann Library Records
University of Houston-Clear Lake Archives & Special Collections
Neumann Library Records
1974-2013
1990-2002
Neumann Library
2014-0003
6 linear feet (12 boxes)
University of Houston-Clear Lake Archives & Special Collections
The Neuman Library, 1974-2013 Records document the careers and initiatives of Francis Weeks and Gay Carter who were librarians at the University of Houston-Clear Lake Neuman Library.
Administrative History
Frances Weeks began working at Neumann Library on March 1, 1996 and served as Coordinator of Access Services, supervising both the interlibrary loan and circulation departments. During her time here, she donated a complete collection of Newbery Medal award winning books to the Curriculum Library. She also was instrumental in the formation of the UHCL Veterans Scholarship Endowment, which she, along with others, helped fund. She was active in the UHCL Veteran's Day Celebrations, The President's Cabinet, and was part of the charter class of Leaders in Action. She retired from the University on January 2, 2014 after 17.5 years of employment.
Gay Carter served as a charter reference librarian from the time the University opened its doors in 1974. In 1980, she began supervising Neumann Library's federal depository and Texas state depository collections. She was active in the Government Documents Round Table of the Texas Library Association, serving as both chair-elect and chair. Gay has been involved for many years in genealogical research and has been a featured speaker, presenter, and writer for several genealogical organizations. She retired from the University in May, 2013.
Scope and Contents of the Records
These are records which were generated or collected by librarians Frances Weeks and Gay Carter during their years at Neumann Library. Included are records relating to the daily processes of running the library, library meeting minutes, policies, memos, fiscal files, library and university events, library brochures and publications, staff information, and general subject files. Both Gay and Frances also served on numerous UHCL Shared Governance Committees and those files are contained herein.
The last three folders of box twelve are closed due to privacy issues.
Access Restrictions
Box 12 contains folders that are closed due to privacy constraints.
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Weeks, Frances; Carter, Gay
Subjects (Organizations)
University of Houston--Clear Lake; Alfred R. Neumann Library
Separated Material
These items were removed from the original donations and placed in the archives' UHCL Memorabilia collection:
Frances Weeks' desk clock given to her for her Leaders in Action participation
UHCL green koozie
Green UHCL Pearland pen
Johnson Space Center green pen
Yarn bomb with attached documentation
Green UHCL folder
Pink UHCL Police department pig with officers' signatures
UHCL t-shirt
UHCL blow horn
Neumann Library book drop sign
These items were sent to technical services to be cataloged for archives:
Faculty & Staff Pictorial Directory 2005
2000-2001 Telephone Directory
2001-2002 Telephone Directory
This item was sent to technical services to be cataloged for the general library collection:
The Library book by Sarah Stewart
Filed into Periodicals:
Various newsletters, UHCLidians, The Signal
Filed into Vertical File:
Most Veterans Day materials
Placed into UHCL Photo Collection:
Veterans Day Celebration 2006 photos on CD
Two photos of Frances Weeks
One 1938 photo of UH Main Campus building site
One 1940 photo of the Houston Municipal Airport
Placed into Broadside collection:
One UHCL smoking policy poster
Related Material
Papers related to subject, but housed in other collections
UHCL Library Records, 2000-0003
UHCL Neumann Library Records, 2003-0004
UHCL Neumann Library Records, 2003-0005
UHCL Neumann Library Records, 2011-0012
UHCL Vertical File Index
Acquisition Information
These files belonged to librarians Frances Weeks and Gay Carter and were donated to the Archives upon their retirement from Neumann Library. Frances' files were donated over the course of several weeks during September and October, 2013. Gay's vertical file records were transferred to the archives in June, 2013 by librarian Martha Steele. This collection is made up of their combined donations
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Series I: Subjects
  - Adjunct Faculty Borrowing Privileges, 1996-1998 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Audit by UH System, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bibliotips, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ceiling Tile Replacement, Upper Floor, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - ChoiceReviews.online, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Circulation Log Book, 1996-1999 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Copiers, 1997-2002 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Copyright Clearance Center, 1997; 2002 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Courier-UH System, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Curriculum Library, 1974; 1974, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Distance Education, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Duplicate Patron Records, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Faculty-Visiting Scholars Privileges, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Filing Assignments, 1986-1989 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Four-Day Work Week/Burnout Articles, 1986-1991 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Friends of the Neumann Library, 1998; 2002 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Furniture/Equipment Requests, 1996; 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Government Documents Biennial Survey, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Government Documents-Maps, 1973; 1986,; undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Government Documents Presentation-Gay Carter, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Houston Teachers Institute, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Interlibrary Loan-Ft. Bend, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Library Brochures, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Library Floor Plans, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Library Organizational Chart, 1993; 1996,; undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Library Space Wars, 2002; 2009 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Lunar and Planetary Institute Borrowers, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Neumann Library Book Lists, 1991-1993 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pearland Library, 2008-2010 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - PeopleSoft, 2000-2005 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - PMI - Clear Lake Chapter, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Reports-Miscellaneous, 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Security System, 1997-2001 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Suggestion Box FY 1996, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Suggestion Box FY 1997, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Suggestion Box FY 1998, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Suggestion Box FY 1999, 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Suggestion Box FY 2000, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Suggestion Box FY 2001, 1999-2001 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Suggestion Box FY 2002, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Suggestion Box FY 2003, 2002-2004 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Susie Swanson Memorial, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Teaching-Learning Enhancement (T-LEC), 2002 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Telephone Directory-Library, 1991; 1993,; undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - TexShare Card Statistics-Yearly, 2001-2009 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - University Archives, 1994; undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - University Archives-JSC History Collection, 2002; 2012 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - UH-University Park, 1982-1986; undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - UHCL Veteran's Scholarship Endowment, 2006-2007; 2013 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Weeding Guidelines, 1996-1999 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Series II: Policies/Procedures
  - Circulation Procedures Manual, Revised May 1992 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Computer Use Policy, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Grievance Policy for Non-Faculty Employee-Draft, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Innovative Interfaces, Inc. (III) Contract, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Library Procedures-General, 1999; 2002,; undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Library Users Policy, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Outside Borrowers and Interlibrary Loan Policies, 2001-2002 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Privacy Notice Forms, 2001-2002 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - TexShare Protocol, 1995-1998 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Circulation Procedures Manual, Revised May 1992 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Computer Use Policy, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Grievance Policy for Non-Faculty Employee-Draft, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Innovative Interfaces, Inc. (III) Contract, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Library Procedures-General, 1999; 2002,; undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Library Users Policy, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Outside Borrowers and Interlibrary Loan Policies, 2001-2002 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Privacy Notice Forms, 2001-2002 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - TexShare Protocol, 1995-1998 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Series III: Meetings (Library)
  - Circulation Staff Meetings, 1996-1999 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Circulation Subgroup Committee, 2001; 2007-2011 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Consortium of Academic Libraries & Academic Resources (CALLR), 1988 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Director's Advisory Group (DAG), 2006; 2009 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Librarians' Meetings, 1983-1987 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Librarians' Meetings, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Librarians' Meetings, 1992-1995 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Librarians' Meetings, 1996-1999 (Box 4, Folder 2-4)
  - Librarians' Meetings, 2002-2011 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Library Retreat, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Library Retreat, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Library Retreat, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Library Retreat, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Public Services Meetings, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Public Services Meetings, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Public Services Meetings, 1998-1999 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Public Services Meetings, 2000-2002 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Public Services Meetings, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Public Services Meetings, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Series IV: Shared Governance
  - Shared Governance-General, 1991; 2006 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Academic Council, 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Component Analysis, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Facilities and Support Services Committee (FSSC), 2007-2008 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Facilities Resource Committee (FRC), 1992 (Box 5, Folder 9-10)
  - Facilities Resource Committee (FRC), 1993 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
  - Faculty Development and Support Fund Committee, 1990-1991 (Box 6, Folder 3-4)
  - Faculty Senate, 1989-1990 (Box 6, Folder 5-6)
  - Faculty Senate, 1990-1991 (Box 6, Folder 7-8)
  - Faculty Senate, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
  - Faculty Senate, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Faculty Senate, 1996-1997 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Faculty Senate Facilities Committee, 1989-1991 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Faculty Vote of No-Confidence in Stauffer, 1993; 2000 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - International Education Committee, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Parking/Traffic Safety Committee, 1994-1995 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Resources and Facilities Planning Board, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Resources and Facilities Planning Committee, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Resources and Facilities Planning Committee, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - Total Quality Management Committee, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - University Life Committee, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - University Life Committee, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - University Life Committee, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - University Life Committee, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - University Life Committee, 1995-1996 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - University Life Committee, 2000-2002 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Series V: Correspondence
  - Memorandums, 1976-1983 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Memorandums, 1984-1987 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Memorandums, 1991-1996 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Memorandums, 2001-2012 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Series VI: Library Committees
  - Biennial Planning Committee, 2006 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Committee for Appointment and Promotion (CAP), 2008 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Circulation Supervisor Search Committee, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Copyright Committee, 1995-1996 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Social Committee, 2010-2011 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Series VII: Librarian-Related Files
  - By-laws and Governance for Librarians, 1988; 1990 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - By-laws Revision, 2006-2009 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Collection Development, 2002-2003 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Faculty Status for Librarians, 1988-1989 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Liaison Librarian Contacts, 2008 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Liaison Librarian for Communications, 2005-2007 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Liaison Librarian for Communications/Digital Media, 2008 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Liaison Librarian for Communications/Digital Media, 2009 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Liaison Librarian for Communications/Digital Media, 2010 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Liaison Librarian for Communications/Digital Media, 2012 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Liaison Librarian for Geography, 2007 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Liaison Librarian for Geography, 2008 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Liaison Librarian for Geography, 2009 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Liaison Librarian for Geography, 2010 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Liaison Librarian for Geography, 2012 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Librarian Salaries, Scholarship, and Professional Development, 2012 (Box 10, Folder 21)
- Series VIII: Fiscal
  - Application for Federal Assistance, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Library Budget, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Money-Change Machine, 1997-2005 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Neumann Library Strategic Plan, 1993; 1998,; undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Series IX: Events
  - Library Exhibit--Judy Chicago Setting the Table, 2011 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Veterans Day, 2006-2007; 2011-2012 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Events, 2009-2011 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Series X: Associations
  - Alumni Association, 2013; undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Bay Area Library Association, 1981-1991 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Professional and Administrative Staff Association (PASA), 1992-1993 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Texas Educational Secretaries Association (TESA) and Educational Secretaries Association (ESA), 2001-2002 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Women's Association, 1980-1984; 1989 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Women's Association-Newsletters, 1980-1989 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Series XI: Publications
  - Library Newsletters--Miscellaneous, 1989-1990 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Between the Stacks Newsletter, 2005-2007 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Series XII: Personnel
  - Christa George-UHCL Early Achievement Award, 2011 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Frances Weeks Personal Mementos, 1995-2013 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Frances Weeks' Professional Librarian Binder--Resume, 2014 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Frances Weeks' Professional Librarian Binder--Job Descriptions, 1992; 1994,; 2000 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Frances Weeks' Professional Librarian Binder--Organization Charts, 1998-2001 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Frances Weeks' Professional Librarian Binder--Meetings/Seminars, 1996-2000 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Frances Weeks' Professional Librarian Binder--Procedures, 1996-1998 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Frances Weeks' Professional Librarian Binder--Committees, 1999-2001 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Frances Weeks' Professional Librarian Binder--EPCC, 1997-2003 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Frances Weeks' Professional Librarian Binder--TExpress, 1998-2000 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Frances Weeks' Professional Librarian Binder--User Survey, 1996-1998 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Frances Weeks' Professional Librarian Binder--Search Committees, 1998-2001 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Frances Weeks' Professional Librarian Binder--VTLS Circulation, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Frances Weeks' Professional Librarian Binder--Contacts, 1998-2004 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Frances Weeks' Professional Librarian Binder--Outside Contacts, 1996-2001 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Frances Weeks' Professional Librarian Binder--TQM, 1996-1997 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Frances Weeks' Professional Librarian Binder--Certificates, 1996-2002 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Job Descriptions-Generic, 1989-2007 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - S. Joe McCord, Library Executive Director, 1994; 2011 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Photos of Library Staff, undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
- Series XIII: Training
  - A Course on Effective Communication & Satisfying Relationships, undated (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Customer Service Skills, undated (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Education & Training in Indexing for Document and Information Retrieval, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Public Relation & Communication Seminar, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Reference Desk Training Binder, 1994-1997 (Box 12, Folder 23)
- Series XIV: Closed Files
  (These files are closed due to privacy issues)
  - Job Descriptions of Individuals (closed), 1987-1990; undated (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous Personnel Records (closed), 1994-2010 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Student Incident Concerning Library Threats on Twitter-(closed), 2009 (Box 12, Folder 26)